CHRISTOPHER DICKSON

PROCESS AUTOMATION ENGINEER

INFO

ADDRESS

53 Telford Road, Glasgow, G75 OHZ, Scotland

PHONE

07784147208

EMAIL

chris.dickson1994@gmail.com

DATE / PLACE OF BIRTH

1994-10-31 Glasgow

NATIONALITY

British

SKILLS

Python (pandas, scikit, numpy, flask. django)

Java

C#

Linux

Bash Scripting

git

PHP

MSSQL

LUA

AWS

MySQL

Qlik

Javascript

VBA

LANGUAGES

English

• • • • •

PROFILE

Experienced Consultant Software Engineer with a demonstrated history of working in the financial services industry. Skilled in Python, SQL, QlikView, PHP, and more. Strong engineering professional with a Bachelor of Science - Computing focused in Computer Software Engineering from Glasgow Caledonian University.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Automation Engineer, Verint Systems

Glasgow

Apr 2019 - Present

- Work closely with other teams to assist them in automating their own testing.
- Help new hires get up to speed via mentoring, pair programming, and paired/group code reviews.
- Find and fill gaps in current set of automated processes integral in helping team reach 90% automation coverage.
- Update existing automated processes to use modern technologies by converting older tests to use Selenium.

Consultant Software Engineer, Capgemini FS

Glasgow

Jul 2013 - Apr 2019

Client - Department of Work and Pensions (October 2018 - April 2019):

- Integral in the installation of enterprise level data governance and data quality software for the client (Informatica Axon on AWS EC2 running RHEL).
- Created shell and Python scripts to automate parts of the installation process.

Client - Student Loans Company (February 2018 - September 2018):

- Designed updated procedures to ensure compliance with GDPR introduction of regulations.
- Investigated possible strategic solutions and created slide-decks to be presented to senior staff.

Client - Zurich Insurance Group (December 2016 - December 2017):

- Developed a data wrangling and data analytics systems using Python (pandas, jupyter notebook, numpy) and MSSQL. Learned pandas/numpy over the course of the project.
- Created a system that when passed data, parsed it, and consolidated it from different formats into a single output, which was passed to an SQL database.

Client - Lloyds Banking Group (July 2013 - November 2016):

 Development and maintenance of sales reporting systems, deeply involving all aspects of the project life-cycle with a focus on design, build, testing and implementation. • Worked closely with end-user support team and developed internal diagnostic tools to assist in successful assimilation of the new system.

Internal projects within Capgemini FS (Various):

• Worked on Data Visualisation systems using both QlikView and Qlik-sense, providing personnel and bench reports to improve the utilisation of resources in the practice.

EDUCATION

Glasgow Caledonian University, Bachelor of Computing - 2:1

Glasgow

Sep 2016 - Aug 2018

Only attended for the final two years. For my dissertation I used machine learning algorithms to detect botnets on IoT devices based on network logs.

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Small scale Flask/Django projects, building a basic blogging site in each to learn more about them.